Sometimes in life, you have to take your lashes.
The Eyes of Tammy Faye is a drama, history film directed by Michael Showalter.
From the 1960s to the 1980s, evangelist Jim Baker and his ambitious wife, Tammy Faye, rose from humble beginnings to build an empire
based on big-time evangelical Christianity--only for the couple to fall from grace because of some all-too-human sins.
Tammy Faye Bakker, played by Jessica Chastain.
Jim Bakker, played by Andrew Garfield.
Rachel Grover, played by Cherry Jones.
Jerry Falwell, played by Vincent D'Onofrio.
Gary Paxton, played by Mark Wystrach.
Roe Messner, played by Sam Jaeger.
The Eyes of Tammy Faye is a 2021 American biographical drama film directed by Michael Showalter from a screenplay by Abe
Sylvia, based on the 2000 documentary of the same name by Fenton Bailey and Randy Barbato of World of Wonder.
The film tells the story of Tammy Faye Bakker (Jessica Chastain), from her humble beginnings growing up in International Falls,
Minnesota, through the rise and fall of her televangelism career and marriage to Jim Bakker (Andrew Garfield).
Cherry Jones and Vincent D'Onofrio also star.
The film is produced by Chastain's production company, Freckle Films.
The Eyes of Tammy Faye had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival in
September 2021, and was released on September 17, 2021, by Searchlight Pictures.
Critics praised the performances (particularly Chastain's) while criticizing the
screenplay, deeming the film to be inferior to the documentary.
At the 94th Academy Awards, the film won Best Actress (for
Chastain) and Best Makeup and Hairstyling.
Chastain also won the SAG Award and Critics'
Choice Movie Award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of affectation, biography, based on
true story, rise and fall, televangelist.
The tone is emotional.